Guide to the Sanford School of Public Policy records, 1971-[ongoing] UA.22.01.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sanford School of Public Policy records
1971-[ongoing]
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sanford School of Public Policy
UA.22.01.0002
4.5 Linear Feet
6.8 Gigabytes
The Sanford School of Public Policy, originally called the Institute of Policy Sciences and Public Affairs, was established by on July 1, 1971, by then-President of Duke University Terry Sanford. This collection includes administrative records, promotional materials, and event-related materials from the Sanford School of Public Policy.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Electronic records in this collection have been migrated to a library server and digital use copies can only be accessed onsite in the Rubenstein Library Reading Room. To request access, please contact a reference archivist before coming to use these records.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Provenance
Materials transferred to the Archives from the Sanford School of Public Policy.
Historical Note
The Sanford School of Public Policy, originally called the Institute of Policy Sciences and Public Affairs, was established by on July 1, 1971, by then-President of Duke University Terry Sanford. Intended "to focus the attention of the University on urgent and continuting policy problems in American society," the Sanford School provides a framework for student and faculty throughout the University to join together to study issues of public policy in an interdisciplinary manner. Formally renamed the Terry Sanford Institute of Public Policy in 1992, after approval to rename the Institute in honor of Terry Sanford had been granted several years before, the school changed its name again in 2009.
The Sanford School offers undergraduate, master's and doctoral degrees in public policy and international development policy, and operates several research centers and programs, including the Duke Center for International Development, the DeWitt Wallace Center for Media and Democracy, the Center for Strategic Philanthropy and Civil Society, the Hart Leadership Program, and the Program on Global Health and Technology Access. The School hosts a number of annual and regular lectures, and publishes school- and policy-related newsletters.
Collection Overview
This collection includes administrative records, promotional materials, and event-related materials from the Sanford School of Public Policy. Administrative records include memoranda, meeting minutes, reports, working papers, publications, and other materials. These records also include some documents concerning the undergraduate program and may include some student materials. Promotional and event-related materials describe the school's curriculum, academic programs, faculty, research, and events, and include brochures, pamphlets, posters, newsletters, and audio and video recordings of lectures and panels.
Posters; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; Digital moving image formats.; Public policy -- Education.; Public policy -- United States.; Public administration -- Education.; Sanford School of Public Policy; Terry Sanford Institute of Public Policy; Terry Sanford Institute of Public Policy; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Faculty
- Accessions UA1992.0106, UA1997.0022, others, 1971-1997; 1.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The materials in these accessions include administrative records which have not yet been processed. Materials may be restricted and will require processing before use.
  - Administrative files (Box 1)
  - Administrative files (Box 2)
- Accession UA2015.0008, 1985-2014; 2; 3 Linear Feet
  The materials in this series are primarily promotional materials and publications for the Sanford School of Public Policy and its events. These materials describe the school's curriculum, academic programs, faculty, research, and events, and include brochures, pamphlets, newsletters, and reports, as well as a number of posters promoting lectures and other events. These also include two data discs containing images and publishing files for the creation of promotional materials including a fundraising brochure. Files labeled with individual names include promotional materials related to that indivudal's appearance at or appointment to the Sanford School. Other event-related materials include audio or video recordings of several speakers and panel discussions, including an audio recording of the January 2005 Ziedman Colloquium featuring David Broder, David Brooks, and Margaret Warner and a video recording of a speech by Newark, NJ, Mayor Cory Booker in 2009, as well as a copy of a slide presentation given by Bruce Jentleson in 2001 and still images from a talk and book signing by Gene Patterson in 2003. Also included are an unidentified audiocassette and an unidentified electronic video file.
  Audiovisual materials may require the production of an access copy, and are indicated by their format. Electronic materials are indicated by a description of their file size in megabytes. All materials in Box 4 are event posters.
  - Sanford School Faculty Guides, 2009-2014 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sanford Institute Faculty Guides, 2000-2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Duke Center for International Development (DCID) Program in International Development Policy PDIP/Master in International Development Policy MIDP Brochures (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Development Brochure, Sanford Institute (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Internship Fund Dinner & Auction, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Development Materials, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Duke Center for Child and Family Policy (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Program in Policy Analysis & Management, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Multi-Sector Public Policy Program, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sanford Grad Student Directory, 2009-2010, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Master of Public Policy Brochures (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sanford Institute Brochure (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Institute of Policy Sciences Viewbook (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Duke PhD in Public Policy, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Undergraduate Brochure, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Undergraduate Materials (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Graduation Programs, 2010, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Sanford Building Dedication, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Faculty Appointments, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Faculty Appointments, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Appointments, 2008-2014 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rubenstein Hall Architectural Drawings, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Rubenstein Hall Dedication, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sanford Institute Annual Report, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Sanford Institute Annual Report, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - State of the Institute, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Fuqua Survey Results, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Living Public Service, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Sanford Institute postcards (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - NC SIP Brochure (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - DeWitt Wallace Media Fellows Brochure (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Hart Leadership Brochures (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Center for Health Law, Policy and Management (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - US-South Africa Center Launch 2001 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - US-South Africa Center for Leadership (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Bruce Jentleson Interview, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Terry Sanford Obit, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Shimon Peres, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - David Gergen, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Joseph Prueher, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Yegor Gaidar, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Robert Reich, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Ambassadors to Mexico & Canada, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - James Gleick, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Donald Keoguh, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Futrell Award, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Bridging Media Panel, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Zeidman Colloquium, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Zeidman Colloquium, 2005 January 15; audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette UA22010002-CS-02)
    Scope and Contents note
    David Broder, David Brooks, Margaret Warner
  - Rubenstein Hall Dedication, Panel Discussion, foreign policy and health policy, 2005 November 4; VHS (Box 3, Video-cassette UA22010002-VHS-01)
  - Charlotte Temple Art Exhibit Opening, undated; audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette UA22010002-CS-03)
  - Michelle Rhee, Sanford Institute, 2008 November 17; DVCam (Box 3, Video-cassette UA22010002-DVCAM-01)
    CH1: House, CH2: Cam. Mic; Video 525/60, PCM 48 Hz/2ch c.
  - Mayor Cory Booker, Newark NJ, Speech, 2009 February 4; DVCam (Box 3, Video-cassette UA22010002-DVCAM-02)
  - Gene Patterson talk and book signing: images (jpgs), February 19, 2003; 162 Megabytes (Box 3, Data-cd UA22010002-OP-002)
  - "Public Policy Leaders for a Changing Word" presentation by Bruce Jentleson: PowerPoint presentation, September 12, 2001; 38 Megabytes (Box 3, Data-cd UA22010002-OP-004)
  - TSI Fundraising Brochure Art (tiffs, eps, others) in file structure, December 26, 2002; 270 Megabytes (Box 3, Data-cd UA22010002-OP-005)
  - MPP Book: images (tiffs, eps, others) in file structure, April 27, 2005; 490 Megabytes (Box 3, Data-cd UA22010002-OP-003)
  - George Soros, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Colin Powell, Rubenstein Hall Dedication (event poster), 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Thad Cochran, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Paul Rusesabagina, Crown Lecture in Ethics (event poster), 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Shashi Tharoor, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Julian Savulescu, Crown Lecture in Ethics (event poster), 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Garrett Graff, Ruth Marcus, Mark Shields, Jeff Zeleny, Zeidman Colloquium on Politics and the Press (event poster), 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kevin "Kal" Kallaugher, Dwane Poweel, Kevin Bleyer, Adam Chodikoff, Laughing at Power: Satire in American Politics (event poster), 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Thomas Friedman, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - David Brooks, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Peter Bergen, Rebecaa Skloot, Joseph Nye, Neal Lane, Sanford Inaugural Events- Spring Series (event poster), 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Joel Fleishman, Richard Fisher, Cokie Robert, Gail Rosseau, John Harwood, Sanford Inaugural Events- Fall Series (event poster), 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dan Blue, Willam Darity, Sherman James Irene Godinez, Charles Clotfelter, Helen Ladd, Minnie Forte-Brown, R. Sciott Ralls, Robert Korstad, James Leloudis, Leslie Winner, Naomi Feaste, Noah Raper, To Right These Wrongs: Continuing the Work of Terry Sanford (event poster), 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Peter Bergen, Steel Family Lecture (event poster), 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Rebecca Skloot, Crown Lecture in Ethics (event poster), 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - David Goldwyn, U.S.- Canada Energy Relationship Conference - Keynote (event poster), 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Howard Gardner, Crown Lecture in Ethics (event poster), 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Juan Zarate, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Shirin Ebadi, Crown Lecture in Ethics (event poster), 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Erskine Bowles, Alan Simpson, Philip Bennet, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Condoleeza Rice, Ambassador Dave and Kay Philips Family International Lecture (event poster), 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - John Dickerson, Nai-Mailka Henderson, Ben Smith, Jay Hamilton, Zeidman Colloquium on Politics and the Press (event poster), 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Jon Huntsman Jr. (September), Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Jon Huntsman Jr. (October), Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Martin Gilen, Brendan Nyhan, Meredith Sadin, Mac MacCorkle, Alexandra Sirota, Who Does Government Work For? (event poster), 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Marian Wright Edelman, Crown Lecture in Ethics (event poster), 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sen. Richard Lugar, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Rajiv Shah, Terry Sanford Distinguished Lecture (event poster), 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Barton Gellman, Gen. Michael V. Hayden, Robert R. Wilson Lecture (event poster), 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Derek Willis, Brendan Nyhan, Daivd R. Karger, Jeffery Heer, Data + Journalism Series (event poster), 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Steve Kainaur, Mark Fainaru-Wada, Philip Bennett, League of Denial (event poster), 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Evan Ellis, Francisco Monaldi, Patrick Duddy, "Geopolitics of Energy: Venezuela" (event poster), 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pete Buttigieg, Micole Malliotakis, Jame Kim, Julian Castro, Connect to Politics Series (event poster), 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ta-Nehisi Coates, Robert R. Wilson Lecture (event poster), 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fran Townsend and Daniel Benjamin, Robert R. Wilson Lecture (event poster), 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Jeffrey Stern, Journalism & Policy Pop-up (event poster), 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ellen Mickiewicz, No Illusions: the Voices of Future Russian Leaders (event poster), 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Pascal Lamy, Von Der Hayden Lecture/ Duke Global Summit (event poster), 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Roy Cooper, Protecting Community Wealth Series (event poster), 2014-2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified audiocassette tape, undated; audiocassette (Box 3, Audio-cassette UA22010002-CS-01)
  - Zinni.wav, January 31, 2007; 842 Megabytes (Box 3, Data-cd UA22010002-OP-001)
- Accession UA2016.0032, 1974-2006
  - Assorted publications and brochures, 1995-2002, undated (Box 5)
  - Center for Child and Family Policy materials, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Center for Health Policy, Law, and Management Annual Report, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Program brochures, circa 1990-2002 (Box 5)
  - Research abstracts, 1996-1999 (Box 5)
  - Speakers and lectures flyers, 1974-1985, undated; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Sanford panel discussion, 2006 (Box 5, Dvd UA22010002-OP-0006)
    Recording of panel discussion during 2006 Full Frame Film Festival after showing of Terry Sanford and the New South; panel moderated by Judy Woodruff, with Jim Hunt, Dan Blue, Hodding Carter III, Al Hunt, and Thomas Lennon. Recording also includes brief clips of New Orleans street jazz band and awards ceremony, both from Full Frame Festival events.
- Accession UA2017.0010, 1981-2013
  - Agenda Book, Board of Visitors, 1981; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Board of Visitors, 1996 November 15-16 (Box 6)
  - Board of Visitors Summary, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Terry Sanford Outrageous Ambition Award Proposal, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Sanford Annual Fund Planning, 2006-2007 (Box 6)
  - 5000 Hours of Service, 2010 (Box 6)
  - Brochures for new building, original building, 1994-2010 (Box 6)
  - Department Brochures, 2003-2013 (Box 6)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 6)
  - Transforming Lives, Building a Better World: Public Policy Leadership for a Global Community video presentation, undated (Box 6, Optical-disc UA22010002-OP-0007)
  - Sanford Institute's New Building Powerpoint presentation, 2002 April 08 (Box 6, Optical-disc UA22010002-OP-0002)